### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/elbiemoonga (LinkedIn) github.com/Elbie-em (Personal)

github.com/Elbie-em (Personal elbiemoonga.me/ (Portfolio)

### Top Skills

Web Development
Team Leadership
Team Work and Collaboration

## Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
French (Elementary)

### Certifications

**JQuery** 

International Diploma in Computing NCC UK

React Certification

JavaScript

Full-Stack Web Development Certification

### Honors-Awards

Certificate of Excellence
Certificate of Excellence
Certificate of Excellence
Certificate of Achievement

### **Publications**

Picking Numbers Challenge
Evolution of Web Design from HTML to HTML5

# Elbie Moonga

Full-stack Code Reviewer at Microverse || Freelance Web Development Consultant

Lusaka

# Summary

I am a professional Full Stack Developer with over 5 years of experience. Some of my greatest strengths are consistency, efficiency, and being a team player. Assign a task, and I make it my responsibility to keep up the team spirit to deliver on time. I am a very good communicator and find it's easy for me to relate to other people.

I have consistently demonstrated my capacity to make a positive impact regardless of the situation.

I'm not afraid of failure, in fact, I think it is an essential part of the experimental process that gets you to success. Outside of work, I spend a lot of my free time learning new technologies. I have built demo projects from my current stack of development knowledge in order to enhance my career and grow my experience.

I have experience working remotely with engineers from several countries and developed my soft skills through being a mentor to fellow developers.

I have completed certifications and developed experience in order to deliver good services to whoever is in need of my expertise. How can I be of service to you?

### **Current Stack:**

- C#
- Ruby
- Ruby on Rails
- JavaScript
- React & Redux
- Git & Git Flow
- HTML
- CSS
- Bootstrap

- PostgreSQL
- SQLite
- RSpec
- Jest

I am currently open to opportunities, feel free to contact at emoonga1993@gmail.com.

My portfolio can be viewed ---> http://elbiemoonga.me/

# Experience

Microverse

2 years 2 months

Code Reviewer

March 2021 - Present (1 year 1 month)

Remote

- Provide code reviews for students all over the world by reviewing pull requests on projects done using tools like HTML/CSS and Ruby on Rails, Vanilla Javascript, and ReactJS.
- Provide project feedback and suggest changes based on best programming practices.
- Ensure that students understand curriculum material so that industrystandard coding practices are maintained.

Student Mentor

February 2020 - Present (2 years 2 months)

Remote

- Assist junior developers in realizing their dreams as software developers.
- Conduct weekly check-ins to advise, review their projects and have general conversations about things happening in the world.
- Share my experiences as a developer and give guides on best practices that I have learned in order to advance in web development.

Self Employed

Full-Stack Developer

January 2015 - December 2018 (4 years)

Zambia

- Built static websites at no cost for several clients to improve skills

- Built an android application called TESA(Tutors Educational System App) to help school teachers manage their lesson plans and teaching schemes.
- Built an android application called Farmers Hub to assist small scale farmers in growing crops by providing training.

## Education

Microverse

Computer Science · (2020 - 2021)

Middlesex University - United Business Institutes
Bachelor of Business Administration (B.B.A.), Business Administration and
Management, General · (2016 - 2016)

NCC UK- ZCAS University

International Diploma in Computing (IDCS), Computer Science · (2013 - 2014)

Thornhill Boarding and Day School

Cambridge International General Certificate of Secondary Education, High School/Secondary Diplomas and Certificates · (2008 - 2010)